<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Acer Zhou's Blog</title><link>https://acerzhou.info/</link><description>Recent content on Acer Zhou's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:27:56 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://acerzhou.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Week in New Company</title><link>https://acerzhou.info/posts/first-week-in-new-company/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:27:56 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://acerzhou.info/posts/first-week-in-new-company/</guid><description>First Week Experience I just finished my first week in the new place and I would like to write down some thinking on the first week. For new company onboarding, I have a dedicated Trello board for myself tracking things (so far I really enjoyed it). I am still setting up my work laptops, building workflow and habits. I did ship my first PR into prod😁, a really simple change in the website.</description></item><item><title>Git Advanced Skill Git Rebase</title><link>https://acerzhou.info/posts/git-advanced-skill-git-rebase/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:27:56 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://acerzhou.info/posts/git-advanced-skill-git-rebase/</guid><description>Overview and Required Knowledge I have been working with Git for a while. As a developer, version control is one of the key daily workflows. However, git rebase is always something that I have heard of it, but never get a chance to deeply understand and applied in my daily working. In this post, I am going to explore git rebase, and summary how to use it.
Required Knowledge: Git Basic Understanding</description></item><item><title>Recursion</title><link>https://acerzhou.info/posts/recursion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:27:56 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://acerzhou.info/posts/recursion/</guid><description>Background and Audiences In the early this week, I have encounter a problem that can solved by recursion. However, it took me a while to get it solved. In this post, I am going to get couple questions on recursion problem, and practice writing some code.
Audiences
Having basic understanding on Programming Haven&amp;rsquo;t familiar recursion problem Recursion In computer science, recursion is a method of solving a problem where the solution depends on solutions to smaller instances of the same problem.</description></item><item><title>Some Javascript Array Fundamentals</title><link>https://acerzhou.info/posts/some-javascript-array-fundamentals/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:27:56 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://acerzhou.info/posts/some-javascript-array-fundamentals/</guid><description>Overview and background Recently, I am working on some React components, and it involved some manipulation on arrays. In C#, there is powerful Linq giving you pretty much all tools you are going to need. It is powerful and readable. However, Javascript is a different story. I am going to summarise some basic JavaScript Array manipulations.
Audience
People having some basic knowledge Haven&amp;rsquo;t doing manipulation and transformation using JavaScript a lot Some useful JavaScript Array Functions Most common used - push, pop const array = [1, 2, 3, 4, 5]; // add 6 at the end const lengthOfArray = array.</description></item><item><title>Some Reflections on My Job Hunting</title><link>https://acerzhou.info/posts/some-reflections-on-my-job-hunting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:27:56 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://acerzhou.info/posts/some-reflections-on-my-job-hunting/</guid><description>This post is about some reflections on my job hunting experience in past couple of months.
Audience who may get most out of this post:
People looking for jobs such as Software Developer or similar role People having 2 - 4 years experience in IT industry People haven&amp;rsquo;t been looking for jobs for a while, or first time looking for a job Lesson No 1 - Don&amp;rsquo;t trust recruiters Last August, a recruiter reached out to me on LinkedIn, and told me there was a good opportunity in another retailer in Australia.</description></item><item><title>VS Code Plugins</title><link>https://acerzhou.info/posts/vs-code-plugins/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:27:56 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://acerzhou.info/posts/vs-code-plugins/</guid><description>VS Code is one of the best and most popular editors in today&amp;rsquo;s world.
From my understanding, it becomes outstanding from tools in IT due to following reasons:
Lightweight Cross Platform (Windows, Mac, Linux) High quality and multiple plugins Clean and simple UI In this post, I put some plugins I have used in my day to day job, and improve my productivity.
Coding and Scripting Helper TabNine I have been used TabNine for a while, and it is become part of my working flow now.</description></item><item><title>What is Container &amp; Docker</title><link>https://acerzhou.info/posts/docker-101/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:27:56 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://acerzhou.info/posts/docker-101/</guid><description>What is Container &amp;amp; Docker Container
A container is a standard unit of software that packages up code and all its dependencies so the application runs quickly and reliably from one computing environment to another.
Docker
Docker is an open source platform for building, deploying, and managing containerized applications.
Because docker is so popular today, the word docker and container are used interchangeably. However, docker is a way doing container, there are also other technologies can do containers e.</description></item></channel></rss>